GEMECHU TAYE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER



+91 9916 842 170



geme.t07@gmail.com



Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

I am a qualified and professional web developer, educator, and community leader with over 3 years of experience in front-end development and website design. Strong creative and analytical skills. Team player with an eye for detail. In-depth background about me can be found here. https://linktr.ee/gemechutaye

EXPERIENCE

CAMPUS DIRECTOR

July 2021 - Present | Hult Prize Foundation

WEB DEVELOPER AND PROJECT **OFFICER**

Dec. 2018 - April 2021 | Empowering Next Generation

- Lead for the organization of the Hult Prize Foundation, a campus program at Jain University.
- Designed and update the Campus website to kick off the program
- Team player with diverse skill sets and a cooperative mindset with the Core Team and for main operations with different Programs and years of study.
- Leading day-to-day activity, meeting with responsible stakeholders from high-level government officials to potential funding partners, organizing training and different events, and overseeing the organization.
- · Customizing and Designing the organization WordPress website, and Managing Social media presence.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Feb. 2017 - Present | Self-Employed

- 3 years of Experience in Developing a frontend website and the stack I used including HTML, CSS, JS, and MERN Stack
- C-panel Administration and Web Design
- For more than 5 companies, I worked directly with board members and executive officials.

EDUCATION

2021 - 2021

Y COMBINATOR

Startup School for Future Founders Certificate of Completion

2020 - 2024

JAIN UNIVERSITY

Computer Science and Engineering (Specialization in Cloud Technology and Mobile Application)

SKILLS

- Language: C and Java
- Scripting: Javascript ES6/7
- Server Scripting: Node.js (Express)
- Front End: HTML5, CSS3, Saas
- Database: Mysql, MongoDB
- Libraries: React (5-month experience)
- Framework/Responsive Design: BootStrap, Flexbox, SVG
- Operating Systems: macOS, Windows and Linux (Ubuntu)
- Others: Data Structure and Algorithm, MERN Stack, Git & GitHub, GCP, UX & UI, SEO, WordPress,

AWARD

- Bertelsmann Technology Scholarship Program recipient- for the Azure Cloud Architect Challenge (2021)
- 30 Days of Google Cloud Program (2021)
- Study In India Scholarship Recipient
- Top 200 African Innovators (2019)
- The idea to Product, Business Model canvas, and validation. (Startup Weekend in Association with Google)
- Solve IT Innovation competition Bootcamp top 30 winner (2018)